# TETIANA PEUTINA

Saint John, New Brunswick

Phone: 5068980827 // Email: tatiana.peutina@gmail.com // LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/peutina

## **SUMMARY**

QA Engineering experience as well as web development skills and managerial experience help me to support planning, coordinating, and performing activities that support product development and business operations. Provide exceptional service by improving quality, reducing problems and bottlenecks, and ensuring that products are delivered on time. Organize effective communication process with teammates to support high-quality interpersonal relationships.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Technical Languages:** Handelbars.js, ReactJS, Express, Python basics, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, Model View Controller (MVC), Progressive Web Applications (PWA)

Applications: Datadog, Confluence, MongoDB, TestRail, Postman, , Jira, Google Cloud Platform, Git

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Customer Service Engineer / Xerox, Saint John, Canada

MAR 2023 – present

- Perform full range of maintenance on assigned products; including technical diagnostics, drivers installation/removal and customer call assistance.
- Take responsibility for customer satisfaction through proper use of customer management skills and engage the support of other Xerox personnel as required.
- Adhere to proper escalation procedures to resolve customer issues.
- Responsible for supportive participation in team functions and adherence to agreed upon practices and procedures developed by the Team.

## **QA Engineer** / *SoftServe Inc*, Ukraine

OCT 2020 - AUG 2022

- Performed front and backend testing, determined root cause of problems.
- Created requirements traceability matrix, summary reports, collected statistical data, and shared information on product quality status with project managers.
- Kept requirement documentation up to date and updated Test Plan and Test Strategy.
- Communicated within English-speaking environment to help team members to resolve issues and ensure the product met expectations.

#### Account Manager / Megaton Trade House, Ukraine (full-time)

AUG 2006 – AUG 2012

- Ensured that customers' needs were fully understood and met.
- Coordinated purchase procedures and handled problems connected with transportation.
- Calculated prices for goods.
- Kept all requirements up to date.

# **EDUCATION**

Full stack web development, University of New Brunswick, Canada	APR 2023-present
Master of Science: Finance, Lviv Polytechnic National University, Ukraine	DEC 2013
Master of Science: Applied Linguistics, Lviv Polytechnic National University, Ukraine	DEC 2006

# **VOLUNTEERING**

First friend for newcomers: YMCA of Saint John	MAR 2023 – present
Interpreter for newcomers: YMCA of Saint John	MAR 2023 - present
Web application tester: Civic Tech Saint	MAR 2023

### TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

•	First Aid/CPR training/ St John Ambulance:	MAR 2023
•	Git Essential Training: The Basics / LinkedIn	JAN 2023
•	ISTQB Certified Tester / Foundation Level	JUL 2022
•	Postman: Rest API Testing / Udemy	JUL 2022
•	The Complete SQL Bootcamp 2022 / Udemy	JAN 2022
•	API Testing - Postman & JMeter / Udemy	AUG 2021
•	Python Data Structures / Coursera	MAR 2020
•	Getting Started with Python / Coursera	JAN 2020